Justin Evangelista

Full Stack Web Developer | 773.633.7324 | justin.j.evangelista@gmail.com | https://just1nsan3.github.io/my-portfolio/

Summary

My experience with the U.S. Marines allowed me to have leadership roles and quickly learn on the fly. Then exposed myself to freelance photography where I first experienced making a website for displaying my photos. I want to use my creative angle and web development skills to create a site people will love.

Skills & Abilities

- · Solid understanding of HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript
- · ReactJS and NodeJS
- · Django, Python, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, and JQuery.

Experience

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | 2018

- I worked with 2 other members and created an application called "Do Stuff!" The app pulls Yelp and Google API to show events happening in Chicago, while displaying the locations of each event. There are 13 categories that events can fall into so the user can filter through the different events easily. I personally was able to create info windows into the google maps API displaying the event linking you to the yelp page. We used Django and Python for the backend and ReactJS for the frontend.
- Worked on 4 other projects implementing knowledge on front and backend use for each application that included ReactJS, NodeJS, Django, Python, Express, SQL, NoSQL, and MongoDB

RIFLEMAN| UNITED STATES MARINE CORPS, CA | 2015-2016

- Executed, without supervision, effective combat support. Demonstrated ability to adapt to diverse situations during team level movement training.
- In garrison, did extensive work up training for deployments to Afghanistan.

TEAM LEADER | SECURITY FORCES (FAST COMPANY) | 2014-2015

- A reaction force known as Fleet Anti-/Counter-terrorism Security Team for the Marine Corps tasked to plan, evaluate, and supervise the implementation of site-specific security plans to protect assets designated as vital to the national security.
- As a team leader being deployed to Guantanamo Bay, Cuba managing day to day training cycles for 50 + personnel.
 Responsible for the welfare, fitness, morale and discipline of a four man team.

Education

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | JUNE-AUGUST // 2018

• Certification for Completing WDI-Web Development Immersive(Full stack web development)

UNITED STATES MARINE CORPS | 2013-2016 |

- Military Occupation Specialty 0311 Rifleman
- Military Occupation Specialty 8152 Security Forces

COLLEGE OF LAKE COUNTY | 2008 |

· Certified Nurse Assistant